Van den Haag, Ernest; Papers apap135
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Publications, 1949-2000; 2; 7.49 cubic ft.
  - Numbered, 1950-2000; 2.1; 6.17 cubic ft.
    - 404. "Thinking About Crime Again", Commentary, 1983 December (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 15)
    - 405. "The Tourist Menace", The American Spectator, 1984 January (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 16)
    - 406. "Professor Ernest van den Haag Talks Tough on Crime and Pornography", Interview, Dartmouth Review, 1983 November 14 (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 17)
    - 407. "How To Pay for Higher Education", Prospect, 1984 January (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 18)
    - 408. "Life and Death Decisions", Letter to the Editor on "Decisions of Death" by David Bruck, The New Republic, 1984 January 23 (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 19)
    - 409. "Baby Jane Doe", National Review, 1984 February 10 (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 20)
    - 410. "The Origins of Socialism", The American Spectator, 1984 February (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 21)
    - 411. "A Right to Die?" National Review, 1984 May 04 (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 22)
    - 412. Reviews of "The Death Penalty: A Debate", New York: Plenum Publishing, 1983 (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 23)
    - 413. "Politics Against Law", Review of "The Politics of Law: A Progressive Critique", Edited by David Kairys, Michigan Law Review, 1984 February (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 24)
    - 414. "Stronger Laws Needed to Curb Press Abuses", U.S.A. Today, 1984 May 11 (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 25)
    - 415. "Is There A Relationship Between Pornography and Sexual Violence?" Human Sexuality, 1984 August (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 26)
    - 416. "The Insanity Defense: An Exchange", Criminal Justice Ethics, 1963 Winter-1964 Spring (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 27)
    - 417. "Tainted Evidence Threatens No One", U.S.A. Today, 1984 July 09 (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 28)
    - 418. "A Good Word for Deficits", National Review, 1984 August 24 (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 29)
    - 419. "Smashing Liberal Icons: A Collection of Debates" by E.v.d. Haag, Heritage Foundation, 1984 (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 30)
    - 420. "Do We Need Exclusionary Rules?" The Advocate, 1984 September (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 31)
    - 421. Review of "Smashing Liberal Icons", National Review, 1984 November 02 (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 32)
    - 422. "Had We Police Enough, and Time, This Coyness, Scarman, Where No Crime", Daily Telegraph (London), 1984 October 25 (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 33)
    - 423. "Comment on John Caplain's 'Administering Capital Punishment,'" University of Florida Law Review, 1984 Spring (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 34)
    - 424. Reply to Professor Robert Johnson, Justice Quarterly, 1984 December (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 35)
    - 425. "New Arguments Against Capital Punishment", National Review, 1985 February 08 (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 36)
    - 426. "More Nuclear Proliferation Please", New York Times, Op. Ed, 1985 February 11 (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 37)
    - 427. Article on Government Subsidy of Art, U.S.A. Today, 1985 January 31 (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 38)
    - 428. "Limiting Plea Bargaining and Prosecutorial Discretion", Cumberland Law Review, Stamford University, 1984-1985 (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 39)
    - 429. "The Death Penalty Vindicates the Law", ABA Journal, 1985 April (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 40)
    - 430. "Witness Against Pornography", Forum, 1985 May (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 41)
    - 431. "Smokers Have Rights Too", New York Times, 1985 April 09 (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 42)
    - 432. "New Laws Are Needed to Cure Media Excess", U.S.A. Today, 1985 April 12 (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 43)
    - 433. "Refuting Reiman and Nathanson", Philosophy and Public Affairs, 1985 Spring (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 44)
    - 434. Letter on Roger Starr, New York Magazine, 1985 June 10 (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 45)
    - 435. "The Neoclassical Theory of Crime Control", In Theoretical Methods in Criminology, Edited by Robert F. Meier, Sage Publications, 1985 (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 46)
    - 435a. "Deterring Potential Criminals", Research Reports, The Social Affairs Unit, 1985 (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 47)
    - 435b. "Deterring Potential Criminals", Reprinted As "The Neoclassical Theory of Crime Control", Criminal Justice Policy Review, 1986 January (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 48)
    - 436. "Rights and Obligations of Prisoners", New England Journal on Criminal and Civil Confinement, 1985 Winter (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 49)
    - 437. "Meant To Be Selective", Letter to the Editor on "The Death Penalty Lottery" by Representative John Conyers Jr., Sunday New York Times, 1985 July 14 (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 50)
    - 438. "Reflections on Von Bulow", National Review, 1985 July 26 (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 51)
    - 439. "Legalize Those Drugs We Can't Control", Wall Street Journal, 1985 August 08 (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 52)
    - 440. "Abortion: A Civilized Exchange", National Review, 1985 September 06 (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 53)
    - 441. "What Makes Johnny Steal?" Review of "Crime and Human Nature" by Richard J. Herrnstein, Wall Street Journal, 1985 September 12 (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 54)
    - 442. "The Business of American Foreign Policy", Foreign Affairs, 1985 Fall (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 55)
    - 443. Review of "Telling Right from Wrong" by Timothy J. Cooney, The American Spectator, 1985 October (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 56)
    - 444. Reviews of "On Courts and Democracy" and "A Capacity for Outrage" by Arthur Selwyn Miller, Constitutional Commentary, 1985 Summer (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 57)
    - 445. Letter to the Editor on Smoking and Professor John Banzhaf, The G.W. Advocate (George Washington University), 1985 October 07 (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 58)
    - 446. "The Death Penalty Once More", U.C. Davis Law Review, 1985 Summer (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 59)
    - 448. "Symposium Contribution: Challenge and Response", Commentary, 1985 November (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 60)
    - 450. "On Bedside Manners", Review of "The Way of the Physician" by Jacob Needleman, The Washington Times, 1985 August 05 (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 61)
    - 451. "Many Years Off", New York Times, 1985 November 13 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 1)
    - 452. Forum on Drugs, Harper's, 1985 December (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 2)
    - 454. "Interests Incompatible", Review of "Rivalry and Central Planning" by Don Lavoie, Times Literary Supplement, London, 1985 December 06 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 3)
    - 455. Review of "Destroying Democracy" by James T. Bennett, New York Times Book Review, 1985 December 22 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 4)
    - 456. "Must the American Criminal Justice System Be Impotent?" (Lecture September 19, 1985), The Washington Institute for Values in Public Policy, Pace Law Review, 1986 Spring (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 5)
    - 457. "On The Effects of Debate", (In German), Die Grossen Kontroversen I, 1985 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 6)
    - 458. "Debate on the Gay Rights Bill Controversy", The New York Post, 1986 February 20 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 7)
    - 459. "Death and Deterrence", National Review, 1986 March 14 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 8)
    - 460. "War and Peace: Foreign Policy in Belief", The American Spectator, 1986 April (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 9)
    - 461. "Categorical Fuzziness", The National Interest, No. 3, 1986 Spring (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 10)
    - 462. "Pornography, Privacy, and the Bias of Media", Proceedings of the Seventh World Media Conference, 1985 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 11)
    - 463. "The Media and the Social Order", World Media Report, 1986 Winter (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 12)
    - 464. "The Ultimate Punishment: A Defence", Harvard Law Review, 1986 May (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 13)
    - 465. "On Sentencing", In "Punishment and Privilege" Edited by W. Bryon Groves, Harrow and Heston, 1986 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 14)
    - 466. "Stockman's Debacle", Review of "The Triumph of Politics" by David A. Stockman, National Review, 1986 June 06 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 15)
    - 467. Review of "A Theory of Rights" by Carl Wellman, Constitutional Commentary, 1986 Summer (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 16)
    - 468. "Aggiornamento: An Historical Analysis", Crisis, 1986 September (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 17)
    - 469. Review of "Smoking and Society" Edited by Robert Tollison, The American Spectator, 1986 October (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 18)
    - 470. "Penalize the Drug Consumers", The World and I, 1986 October (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 19)
    - 471. "Pornography and the Law", The Heritage Lectures, 1987 January 15 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 20)
    - 471a. "Outlaw Porn", The American Spectator, 1987 July (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 21)
    - 472. "Evolving Standards of Decency Are No Standards", New Jersey Law Journal, 1987 March 19 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 22)
    - 473. "Punishment: Desert and Crime Control", Review of "Past or Future Crimes" by Andrew von Hirsch, Michigan Law Review, 1987 April-1987 May (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 23)
    - 474. "The Utopian Mind", Review of "A Conflict of Visions" by Thomas Sowell, Policy Review, 1987 Spring (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 24)
    - 475. "Can Any Legal Punishments of the Guilty Be Unjust to Them?", "Justice in Punishment and Assumption of Risks" by Hugo Adam Bedau, and "Rejoinder to Bedau's Comments", The Wayne Law Review, 1987 Summer (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 25)
    - 476. "Fight Spread of Aids With: Legal Needles, Mandatory Tests - And Jail", New York Post, 1987 July 13 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 26)
    - 477. "A Living Constitution?" The Heritage Lectures, 1987 April 23 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 27)
    - 477a. "A Living Constitution?" Excerpt Reprinted in The World and I, 1987 September (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 28)
    - 478. "On Conservatism", The American Spectator, 1987 September (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 29)
    - 479. Reviews of "The U.N.: In or Out", N.Y.: Plenum Publishing, 1987 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 30)
    - 480. "Bork v. The Activists", New York Post, 1987 October 16 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 31)
    - 481. "The Last Twenty Years", The American Spectator, 1987 December (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 32)
    - 482. Letter to the Editor on Aids, Commentary, 1988 February (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 33)
    - 483. "Yankee Stay Home", National Review, 1988 April 01 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 34)
    - 484. "A Hard but Practical Line", The Prison Journal, 1987 Winter (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 35)
    - 485. "Religion in the 1980s", National Forum, 1988 Winter (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 36)
    - 486. "Aids and Needles", Letter to the Editor, Commentary, 1988 April (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 37)
    - 487. Review of "The Death Penalty in the Eighties" by Welsh S. White, University of Pittsburgh Law Review, 1988 Winter (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 38)
    - 488. "The Rights of Public Figures", Policy Review, 1988 Spring (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 39)
    - 489. "Not Beyond Conjecture", Letter to the Editor on "When a Reader Cancels" by Paul Johnson, The Spectator, 1988 May 28 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 40)
    - 490. "Lending To Gorbachev", National Review, 1988 July 22 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 41)
    - 491. "A Correction", Letter to the Editor on "They Made It" by Alfred Kazin, Dissent, 1988 Summer (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 42)
    - 492. "Capitalismo E. Liberdade", Visao, 1988 May 04 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 43)
    - 493. Reviews of "U.S. Ends and Means in Central America", National Review, and The Economist, 1988 August 13; 1989 March 10 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 44)
    - 494. Review of "Ambassador in Paris: The Reagan Years" by Evan Galbraith, The American Spectator, 1988 July (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 45)
    - 495. "No Special Treatment", Reason, 1988 October (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 46)
    - 496. Interview on the Death Penalty with Igor Makurin, Echo of the Planet (Russian), 1988 November (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 47)
    - 497. "Why Gorbachev Won't Make It", The National Interest, 1988 Fall (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 48)
    - 498. Correction on "Miscarriages of Justice in Potentially Capital Cases" by Hugo Adam Bedau, Stanford, Undated (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 49)
    - 499. "No Mandate", National Review, 1988 December 09 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 50)
    - 500. "And the Winner Is...", Letter to the Editor on "Picasso and the Woman" by Roger Scruton, National Review, 1988 December 30 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 51)
    - 501. "Social Agency Bureaucrats Hide Behind Confidentiality", New York Post, 1989 January 11 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 52)
    - 502. "The War Between Paleos and Neos", National Review, 1989 February 24 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 53)
    - 502a. Response to "The War Between Paleos and Neos", National Review, 1989 April 07 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 54)
    - 503. "Thoughts on Homeless Today", The American Spectator, 1989 April (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 55)
    - 504. Review of "A Stradegy for Peace" by Sissela Bok, The Washington Times, 1989 March 06 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 56)
    - 505. "Comrade, Can You Spare A Dime?" National Review, 1989 March 24 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 57)
    - 506. "What the Constitution Plainly Protects Is Speech, Not Expression", New York Post, 1989 July 04 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 58)
    - 507. "Discourse on Method", A Letter on Freddie Ayer, The Spectator, 1989 July 29 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 59)
    - 508. "Transcending the Rules of Justice", Letter to the Editor on Alan M. Dershowitz' Review of "Pardons" by Kathleen Dean Moore, The New York Times Book Review, 1989 August 06 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 60)
    - 509. "Kantian Dodge", Letter to the Editor on "Moral Obtuseness in America" by Hadley Arkes, National Review, 1989 August 18 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 61)
    - "Affirmative Action and Campus Racism", Academic Questions, 1989 Summer (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 62)
    - 511. "Confirmed but not Bachelors", National Review, 1989 September 15 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 63)
    - 512. "Murdering the Death Penalty", Review of "Capital Punishment and the American Agenda" by Franklin E. Zimring, Benchmark, 1988 Winter (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 64)
    - "The End of Communism in Italy", National Review, 1989 December 08 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 65)
    - 514. "Murderers Deserve the Death Penalty", The World and I, 1989 November (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 66)
    - 515. "Abortion: The Morality - Is there a Middle Ground?" National Review, 1989 December 22 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 67)
    - 516. "Is the United Nations Useful?" Social Education, 1989 September (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 68)
    - 517. "Why are They Begging?" The American Spectator, 1990 April (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 69)
    - 518. "Never Again", (Against Drug Legalization), National Review, 1990 April 01 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 70)
    - 519. "The Proper Goals of Punishment", American Criminal Law Review, 1989 Spring (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 71)
    - 520. "Involuntary Patrons", Vantage Point, 1990 Spring (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 72)
    - 521. "Crime Without Punishment", National Review, 1990 April 16 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 73)
    - 522. "Young Murderers", The World and I, 1990 April (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 74)
    - 523. Letter to the Editor on "By Cozzens Possessed" by Dwight McDonald, 1958 February (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 75)
    - 524. Letter to the Editor on Paul Goodman, Commentary, 1960 April (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 76)
    - 525. Letter to the Editor on "The Case for Intervention in Cuba" by Irving Kristol, The New Leader, 1962 November 12 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 77)
    - 526. Letter to the Editor on "The Case for a Family Allowance" by Mr. Moynihan, New York Times, 1967 February (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 78)
    - 527. Letter to the Editor on "The Question of Fidelity" by Simone de Beauvoir, Harper's, Undated (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 79)
    - 528. "One Smells a Rat", The Recorder, 1990 March 26 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 80)
    - 529. "On the Common Saying That it is Better that Ten Guilty Persons Escape than that One Innocent Person Suffer: Pro and Con", with Jeffrey Reiman, Social Philosophy and Policy, 1990 Spring (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 81)
    - 530. Letter to the Editor on Capital Punishment, The Criminologist, 1990 May-1990 August (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 82)
    - 531. Letter to the Editor, Commentary, 1990 September (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 83)
    - 531a. "Sex, Bananas, and the Arts", Letter to the Editor, The New Republic, 1990 August 13 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 84)
    - 532. "The Smokescreen of Addiction", National Review, 1990 November 05 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 85)
    - 533. "Social Intercourse", Letter to the Editor, The Spectator, 1990 December 01 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 86)
    - 534. "Prudent Bankers", National Review, 1991 February 25 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 87)
    - 536. "Sodom and Begorrah", National Review, 1991 April 29 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 88)
    - 537. Letter to the Editor on "Ex Cathedra", The New Republic, 1991 May 13 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 89)
    - 538. "The Arts and Public Funding", Selections from Debate at the NALAA Convention, Connections, 1990 September (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 90)
    - 539. "Le Finalita Specifiche Della Sanzione Penale", Biblioteca Della Leberta, 1991 April (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 91)
    - 540. "The Desolation of Reality", The World and I, 1991 July (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 92)
    - 541. "On Centesimus Annus", National Review, 1991 June 24 (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 93)
    - 541. "Emmet Till", Letter to the Editor, American Scholar, 1991 Summer (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 94)
    - 542. "The Morality of Capital Punishment", Duquesne Law Review, 1991 Summer (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 95)
    - 550. "The Lex Talionis Before and After Criminal Law", Criminal Justice Ethics, 1991 Winter-1992 Spring (Box 6 (2-Publications), Folder 96)
    - 551. "Why Do American Children Learn So Little?" National Review, 1992 August 03 (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 1)
    - 551. "For Capital Punishment", Isreal Law Review, 1991 Summer-Fall (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 2)
    - 552. "At the Final Exit In Need of Help", On Suicide, The Wall Street Journal, 1992 October 13 (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 3)
    - 553. Letter to the Editor on Jenny Teichman's "The False Philosophy of Peter Singer", The New Criterion, 1993 June (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 4)
    - 554. "Is Liberalism Just?" Review of "Political Liberalism" by John Rawls, The Public Interest, 1993 Fall (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 5)
    - 555. "An Expert Witness Disagrees: A Recantation", National Review, 1993 November 01 (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 6)
    - 559. "How to Cut Crime", National Review, 1994 May 30 (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 7)
    - 563. "How Is Entitlement Deserved?" Public Affairs Quarterly, 1994 (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 8)
    - 566. "Is War Unavoidable?" Chronicles, 1995 October (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 9)
    - 566. Letter to the Editor on "The Bell Curve" by Charles Murray, Commentary, 1995 August (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 10)
    - 567. "Crime: Age and Criminality", Chronicles, 1996 March (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 11)
    - 569. "In Praise of the Wag Gap", Wall Street Journal, 1996 June 29 (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 12)
    - 570. "Hospitals and Hotels", Chronicles, 1996 October (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 13)
    - 571. "Whose Life Is It?" Criminal Law Bulletin, 1997 May-1997 June (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 14)
    - 573. "Vengence Must Be Ours", Letter to the Editor on "Abolish the Death Penalty, Officially" by John Dilulio, 1997 December 30 (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 15)
    - 574. "Peter Shaw", Memorial Special Issue, Academic Questions, Vol. 9, No. 5, Undated (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 16)
    - 575. "Why Does Suicide Have a Bad Reputation?" Chronicles, 1998 August (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 17)
    - 577. "Reflections on Punishment", Criminal Law Bulletin, 2000 July-2000 August (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 18)
  - Unnumbered, 1960-1998; 2.2; 0.33 cubic ft.
    This subseries contains publications not numbered by van den Haag. They are internally arranged the same as subseries 1, but externally in chronological order by date published.
    Arranged chronologically.
    - "Creating Cities for Human Beings", The Municipal South, 1960 May (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 19)
    - "Homosexuality - A Disease?" Drum, 1965 July (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 20)
    - "Treatment of Woman Prisoners Verses male Prisoners", Appearance on Take Two, Cable News Network, 1983 January 14 (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 21)
    - "A Look at Vigilante Justice: Taking the Law into Your Own Hands", Appearance on Freeman Reports, Cable News Network, 1984 December 28 (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 22)
    - Letter to the Editor on "Between Guilt and Innocence" by John P. MacKenzie, Unidentified, 1985 August 16 (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 23)
    - Letters to the Editor, London Review of Books, 1986 August 01 (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 24)
    - Wrong Turns on the Road to Judicial Activism, Assistant Attorney General's Office of Legal Policy, 1987 September 25 (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 25)
    - Review of "Feminism and Freedom" by Michael Levin, Policy Review, 1988 (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 26)
    - "A Correction", Letter to the Editor Correcting Alfred Kazin's "They Made It", Dissent, 1988 Summer (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 27)
    - Letter to the Editor, Wall Street Journal, 1989 January 15 (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 28)
    - "Adverse Inferences from Silence", Assistant Attorney General's Office of Legal Policy, 1989 January 31 (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 29)
    - "Legal Punishment", American Criminal Law Review, 1989 Spring (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 30)
    - "The Proper Goals of Punishment", Discussion with Charles Murray and Barry Slotnick, American Criminal Law Review, 1989 Spring (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 31)
    - "Up from Blackstone", Fortune, 1990 July 02 (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 32)
    - "Art, Nightmares, and David Lynch", Letter to the Editor, National Review, 1990 October 15 (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 33)
    - "The Morality of Capital Punishment: An Exchange", Duquesne Law Review, 1991 Summer (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 34)
    - "For Capital Punishment", Israel Law Review, 1992 (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 35)
    - "Thinking About Rape", The American Spectator, 1992 April (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 36)
    - "Does Democracy Make Girls Prettier?" Fortune, 1992 November 02 (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 37)
    - "Who Goes Homeless?" National Review, 1993 March 01 (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 38)
    - "Causes, Alleged and Actual, of the L.A. Riots", Southern California Law Review, 1993 May (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 39)
    - "Smoking Anyone?" The Atlantic Monthly, 1994 (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 40)
    - "Academic Freedom and Tenure", Pace Law Review, 1994 Fall (Box 7 (2-Publications), Folder 41)